ALEKSEY POTAPOV

Senior iOS Developer

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Bratislava Slovakia

PHONE

+421949474199

EMAIL

ing.aleksey.potapov@gmail.com

SKILLS

iOS Development: since 2012

Objective-C: 8+ years of professional experience

Swift: 6 years of professional experience

Familiar with: SwiftUI, Combine

Scripting Languages: Python, Bash, Ruby

Git and Gitflow for version control

Agile Scrum and Kanban workflows

Familiar with Java, Kotlin

Mostly used: Apple CarPlay, Core Location, Core Bluetooth, RxSwift, MVVM approach, Unit Testing, Dependency Injection

Mentoring and knowledge sharing

LANGUAGES

Russian, Ukrainian (Native)

English (C1 level)

Slovak (B2 level), Czech (A2 level)

German (A2 level)

PROFILE

I am iOS Developer with 8+ years of professional experience, focusing on the result along with a quality of code. Performing mentoring and internal workshops for colleagues. I like simplicity and clean design when developing applications, writing unit tests for code coverage and creating reliable applications. I follow Apple Human Interface Guidelines to bring more benefits for users.

More info: https://alekseypotapov.dev

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

iOS Developer, Sygic a.s.

Bratislava, Slovakia

Aug 2017 — Present

Sygic GPS Navigation app: implementing new features using Sygic SDK, RxSwift and MVVM architecture

Onlia Sense app: implementation from scratch till shipping using Swift, Firebase, Twilio, writing Unit Tests

Sygic CarNavi app: integrated Apple CarPlay, SmartDeviceLink and other 3rd party libraries for automotive

iOS Developer, Alice in Tokyo

Bratislava, Slovakia

Mar 2015 — Jul 2017

Internet of Things projects

My role: implement connection to smart devices on local network using Objective-C, Swift, ReactiveCocoa, Typhoon framework for Dependency Injection, Swift Protocol-Oriented Programming, Alljoyn framework

iOS Developer, Mobindustry Corp.

Dnipro, Ukraine

Jun 2013 — Aug 2014

Outsourcing various projects using Core Location, creating user profile builder, custom iOS camera, custom UI elements

Mentoring, BrainBasket Foundation

Bratislava, Slovakia

Sep 2017 — Mar 2018

Organizing and leading workshop classes during Harvard CS50's course

EDUCATION

Master of Science in engineering, Applied Bratislava, Slovakia Informatics, Slovak University of Technology

Sep 2014 — Jun 2016